Susan Caperna Lloyd collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 7: Holy Week religious ritual
  - Subseries 5: Guatemala
    - Palm Sunday, Chichicastenango Church/Mayan devotees with incensarios, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2466-PH2479; 14 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Stelae at Tikal archeological site depicting ancient Mayan sacrifice and incensarios, Tikal, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2480-PH2504; 25 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Decorations of fertility, Holy Week, Santiago, Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2505-PH2526; 22 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Maximón, Mayan puppet-deity (half old god and new) and devotees at Confraternity of Santa Cruz, Tuesday of Holy Week, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2527-PH2549; 23 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Procession of bullroarers as Maximón is carried by a Mayan brujo to municipal building then to his private capilla (chapel), Holy Wednesday, Santiago, Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2550-PH2607; 58 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Maximón in his capilla, Holy Wednesday through Good Friday, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2608-PH2627; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Holy Thursday feast with townspeople bringing food to outdoor table, reenacting the Last Supper, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2628-PH2644; 17 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Church scenes, Good Friday, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2645-PH2660; 16 color slides (35 mm) (Box 13)
    - Church scenes, Good Friday, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2661-PH2680; 20 color slides (35 mm) (Box 14)
    - Cross raising in church, Good Friday, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2681-PH2699; 19 color slides (35 mm) (Box 14)
    - Good Friday procession and burial of child in cemetery, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2700-PH2769; 70 color slides (35 mm) (Box 14)
    - Procession of Virgin, Good Friday, and dancing with Virgin on Holy Saturday, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2770-PH2799; 30 color slides (35 mm) (Box 14)
    - Portraits of children and villagers, Holy Week, Santiago Atitlán and Sololá, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2800-PH2833; 34 color slides (35 mm) (Box 14)
    - Holy Week carpets made with dyed sawdust over which statues are carried on Good Friday, Antigua, Guatemala; procession/church steps, Good Friday, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2834-PH2857; 24 color slides (35 mm) (Box 14)
    - Good Friday procession, Sololá, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2858-PH2874; 17 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
    - Holy Week offerings to Mayan pre-Christian deity, Pascual Abaj, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2875-PH2908; 34 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
    - Portraits and town views, Holy Week, Sololá and Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2909-PH2937; 29 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
    - Scenic views, Holy Week, Santiago Atitlán, Guatemala, 1989, AFC 2018/064: PH2938-PH2956; 19 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
  - Subseries 6: Mexico
    - Carnival (last day of revelry before Lenten season begins), Tepoztlán, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH2957-PH2993; 37 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
    - Lenten pilgrimage to Chalma church and Devil Dancers, Chalma, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH2994-PH3042; 49 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
    - Palm Sunday, Tepoztlán, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH3043-PH3076; 34 color slides (35 mm) (Box 15)
    - Cactus bearing flagellantes, Good Friday, Taxco, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH3077-PH3199; 123 color slides (35 mm) (Box 16)
    - Procession of Mary meeting Christ with cross and Veronica with cloth to wipe Christ's face, Good Friday, Taxco, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH3200-PH3242; 43 color slides (35 mm) (Box 16)
    - Women's Procession of Silence, Good Friday, Taxco, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH3243-PH3268; 26 color slides (35 mm) (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous processions and town views, Good Friday, Taxco, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH3269-PH3282; 14 color slides (35 mm) (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous processions and town views, Good Friday, Taxco, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: PH3283-PH3305; 23 color slides (35 mm) (Box 17)
    - Tepoztlán/Taxco, Mexico, 1991, AFC 2018/064: SL-12-01 – SL-12-09; 245 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-12-01: Tepoztlán, Mexico Candelaria; Scanned (8/22/18) 36, 4A, 14A, 12A, 22, 21; Printed (8/22/18) 36, 4A, 14A, 22, 21; SL-12-02: Missing 28-32; SL-12-03: Taxco, Mexico, Good Friday; 3-32; SL-12-04: Complete; SL-12-05: Complete; SL-12-06: 17-21, 25-35; SL-12-07: Tepoztlán Carnival; 2-11; SL-12-08: Tepoztlán Carnival; 11-36; SL-12-09: Tepoztlán, Candelaria.; Kodak 5052; Kodak 5063; Kodak 5062; Ilford. (Box 21)
    - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-12], 1 folder (Box/folder 37/7)
    - Tarahumara, Norogachi, Mexico notebook, 2001, 1 notebook (Box/folder 30/4)
    - Tarahumara Indian plaza and church, Copper Canyon views, Holy Week, Norogachi, Mexico, 2001, AFC 2018/064: PH3658-PH3670; 13 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
    - The Tarahumara portray fariseos (enemies of Christ) and soldados (soldiers of Christ), dancing in mock combat, Good Friday, Norogachi, Mexico, 2001, AFC 2018/064: PH3671-PH3705; 35 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
    - The Tarahumara portray fariseos (enemies of Christ) and soldados (soldiers of Christ), dancing in mock combat, Good Friday, Norogachi, Mexico, 2001, AFC 2018/064: PH3706-PH3742; 37 color slides (35 mm) (Box 19)
    - Tarahumara Way of the Cross procession and burning of Judas, symbol of oppressive Ladino landowner, Good Friday, Norogachi, Mexico, 2001, AFC 2018/064: PH3743-PH3776; 34 color slides (35 mm) (Box 19)
    - Sketches and observations made by Gail Caperna, Susan Lloyd's mother, Potam, Yaqui Village, Mexico, 2002, Gail Caperna; 1 notebook (Box/folder 30/5)
    - Yaqui Indians portray chapayekas (enemies of Christ along with fariseos) and soldados (soldiers of Christ) in mock battles, Good Friday, Hermosillo, Mexico, 2002, AFC 2018/064: PH3510-PH3538; 29 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
    - Yaqui Indians portray soldados, burning a Judas figure and swords of the fariseos on Holy Saturday, Hermosillo, Mexico, 2002, AFC 2018/064: PH3539-PH3570; 32 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
    - Yaqui Indians portray soldados, "converting" the fariseos with flowers, Holy Saturday, Hermosillo, Mexico, 2002, AFC 2018/064: PH3571-PH3594; 24 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
    - The Yaquis ramada of the Virgin and resurrected Christ; plaza, crowd scenes, children's groups, Holy Saturday, Hermosillo, Mexico, 2002, AFC 2018/064: PH3595-PH3621; 27 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
    - A Yaqui Deer Dancer, appears after the fariseos conversion, dancing with musicians in his ramada, Holy Saturday, Hermosillo, Mexico, 2002, AFC 2018/064: PH3622-PH3657; 36 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
  - Subseries 7: Spain
    - Marchas Procesionales en Sevilla, 1994, AFC 2018/064: SR022; 1 sound cassette
    - Costaleros, carriers of pasos (platforms) which hold statues depicting Christ, Mary, and figures in Passion story, Good Friday, Seville, Spain, 1998, AFC 2018/064: PH3306-PH3337; 32 color slides (35 mm) (Box 17)
    - Hooded confraternities (nazarenos) accompany pasos carried in numerous processions, Good Friday, Seville, Spain, 1998, AFC 2018/064: PH3338-PH3399; 62 color slides (35 mm) (Box 17)
    - Procession of the Virgin, La Macarena, Good Friday, Seville, Spain, 1998, AFC 2018/064: PH3400-PH3434; 35 color slides (35 mm) (Box 17)
    - Street scenes, Columbus tomb and Holy Week window displays, Seville, Spain, 1998, AFC 2018/064: PH3435-PH3462; 28 color slides (35 mm) (Box 17)
    - Seville, Spain, 1998, AFC 2018/064: SL-15-01 – SL-15-03; 79 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-15-01: Missing 1-3; SL-15-02: 15-18, 22-36; SL-15-03: Complete.; Ilford HP5 (Box 21)
    - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-15], 1 folder (Box/folder 37/10)
    - Young men (los empalaos), wearing their mother's embroideries and tied to crossbeams emulating Christ's cross, process through the streets on Good Friday, Valverde de la Vera, Spain, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH3463-PH3495; 33 color slides (35 mm) (Box 17)
    - Young men (los empalaos), wearing their mother's embroideries and tied to crossbeams emulating Christ's cross, process through the streets on Good Friday, Valverde de la Vera, Spain, 2005, AFC 2018/064: PH3496-PH3509; 14 color slides (35 mm) (Box 18)
- Series 8: Oregon
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Pendleton, Oregon Round-Up, 1978, AFC 2018/064: PH0801-PH0816; 16 slides (35mm); 801, Indians socialize next to three American Quarter Horses; 802, Rodeo contestants wait by the fence; 803, Indian girls peer through the fence; 804, American Quarter Horses waiting for roping competition; 805, "Miss Rodeo Wyoming" among crowd outside Let R Buck bar room; 806, American Quarter Horses wait for competition; 807, Rodeo contestant number four hundred and sixteen watches Indian parade inside ring; 808, Indians in parade on Pendleton Street; 809, Indian boy in parade on Pendleton Street; 810-811, Indians in parade on Pendleton Street; 812, Crowd watches Pendleton Round-Up; 813, Waiting Quarter Horses; 814, Indian girls peer over fence; 815, Men in cowboy hats watch the Pendleton Round-Up; 816, Painting of Amos Pond/dedication to the American Cowboy outside arena. (Box 5)
    - Modoc Indians, 1978-1988, 1 folder (Box/folder 30/6)
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Spirits of Captain Jack, about 1872-1873 Modoc War in Oregon/California and folk legend Captain Jack, the Modoc leader, 1988, AFC 2018/064: P-01
      - Lava Beds Underground with map showing location #12 of solstice pictograph, AFC 2018/064: P-02
      - Letter to Susan Lloyd from Mary Benteron, Lava Beds Park Ranger, with flyers on Modoc culture, folklore, medicinal plants, and the Modoc wars, September 13, 1988, AFC 2018/064: P-03
      - Park Service brochure showing folk legend Captain Jack's stronghold, shamanic medicine flag and dance ring locations. Brochure by Lava Beds Natural History Association, 1978, AFC 2018/064: P-04
      - Lava Beds National Monument Bird Field Checklist; also brochure with map and reproduced engravings from Illustrated London News, 1872-1873, showing Modoc War battleground, AFC 2018/064: P-05
      - Klamath Basin National Wildlife Refuge in California and Oregon, a brochure showing seasonal wildlife highlights. Also Lloyd photo of Tule Lake and geese, June 1983, AFC 2018/064: P-06
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Spirits of Captain Jack, describing descent into Modoc cave to find solstice pictographs. The pictograph depicts the sun, horizon lines, and natural indentation in the rock. The sun is in negative, its outline formed by lichen growing around where original paint was, 1400 AD, 1988, AFC 2018/064: P-07
    - England; New Mexico; Ashland, Oregon notebook, 1985-1986, 1 notebook (Box/folder 25/10)
    - Oregon folk life (1 of 3), 1985-1991, 1 folder (Box/folder 30/7)
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, The Wild Fish, about salmon fishing culture on Rogue River in southern Oregon, 1985, AFC 2018/064: Z-01
      - Guest column by Susan Lloyd, When the Wild Fish Run on the Rogue, in Ashland Daily Tidings, February 15, 1986, AFC 2018/064: Z-02
      - Article by Susan Lloyd, The Wild Fish, in Lithiagraph, Volume 2, Number 11, about salmon fishing culture on the Rogue River in southern Oregon, November 1985, AFC 2018/064: Z-03
      - Guest opinion by Susan Lloyd, Wild Fish Return -- To Spawn and Die in the Rogue River, in The Oregonian, about salmon fishing culture on the Rogue River in southern Oregon, 1985, AFC 2018/064: Z-04
      - Article by Susan Lloyd, Return of the Salmon, in Siskiyou Country, Number 23, pages 24-26, about salmon fishing culture on the Rogue River in southern Oregon, April-May 1986, AFC 2018/064: Z-05
      - Article by Susan Lloyd, The Wild Fish, in the Flying Springbok, pages 76-79, about salmon fishing culture on the Rogue River in southern Oregon, 1987, AFC 2018/064: Z-06
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Part-Time Hobo, about her experiences freight-hopping in the southern Oregon mountains, looking for the legendary "golden spike," and related hobo folk legends, 1986, AFC 2018/064: Z-07
    - Oregon folk life (2 of 3), 1985-1991, 1 folder (Box/folder 30/8)
      - Essay by Susan Lloyd, In Snow, Remember Romance of the Rails, in The Oregonian, page E11. About freight hopping, looking for the "golden spike," and related hobo folk legends, December 25, 1986, AFC 2018/064: Z-08
      - Essay by Susan Lloyd, Part-Time Hobo (edited by publisher), in Siskiyou Journal, Number 27, about her experiences freight hopping and related hobo folk culture, December 1986-January 1987, AFC 2018/064: Z-09
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, A Saturday in Portland, about memories of childhood haunts versus post-modern architectural changes in Portland, Oregon, 1986, AFC 2018/064: Z-10
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Labor Day Blues, about end-of-summer holiday, Labor Day, and attendant societal expectations, 1986, AFC 2018/064: Z-11
      - Opinion piece by Susan Lloyd, Those Labor Day Blues, in Ashland Daily Tidings, page 4. About end-of-summer holiday, Labor Day, and attendant societal expectations, September 5, 1987, AFC 2018/064: Z-12
      - Essay by Susan Lloyd, Big Mama: Notes of a Native Daughter in Siskiyou Journal, Number 28, about Lloyd's neighborhood cat problem in Ashland, Oregon, February-March 1987, AFC 2018/064: Z-13
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, The Sacred Place, about mythic life cycle of migrating Oregon Chinook salmon and relationship to her students' quests in the study of photography at the University of Oregon, 1987, AFC 2018/064: Z-14
      - Essay by Susan Lloyd, Notes of a Native Daughter, in Siskiyou Journal, Number 29, page 4. About mythic life cycle of migrating Oregon Chinook salmon and relationship to her students' quests in the study of photography at the University of Oregon, April-May 1987, AFC 2018/064: Z-15
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Career Education in Yreka, about carnival folklore and a feud between two "carnies" and a resultant homicide, 1988, AFC 2018/064: Z-16
    - Oregon folk life (3 of 3), 1985-1991, 1 folder (Box/folder 31/1)
      - Article by Susan Lloyd, Career Education in Yreka: The People vs. Derrick Wallace, in Siskiyou Journal, Number 32, pages 14-16, about carnival worker folklore and a feud between two "carnies" and a resultant homicide, December 1987-January 1988, AFC 2018/064: Z-17
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Video Fever, about the renting of VHS movies and growing societal addiction to watching movies at home which predated Netflix thirty years later, 1989, AFC 2018/064: Z-18
      - Essay by Susan Lloyd, Video Madness, in Rogue Valley Magazine, page 14, and in Siskiyou Journal, Number 32, pages 14-16, February-March 1989, AFC 2018/064: Z-19
      - Manuscript by Susan Lloyd, Looking for Christmas, about search for the "perfect" Christmas, 1990, AFC 2018/064: Z-20
      - Essay by Susan Lloyd, Looking for Christmas, in Rogue Valley Magazine, page 16, about search for the "perfect" Christmas, December 1990-January 1991, AFC 2018/064: Z-21
      - Map made for Susan Lloyd by old-timer and owner of Craft Rock Shop in Lakeview, Oregon. It shows the route to get from Lakeview to the Hart Mountain Wildlife refuge and the area in the Rabbit Hills where the legendary "plush diamonds" are found. Also a letter of inquiry from Susan Lloyd to Oregon Magazine for an article on the plush diamonds, AFC 2018/064: Z-22
    - Ashland During Coronavirus: A Snapshot Journal, March-June 2020 (Box/folder 39/4)
    - Portfolio 15: Ashland During Coronavirus: A Snapshot Journal, 2020, These photographs were taken with an iPhone (cell phone) during two months of quarantine during the beginning of the Coronavirus pandemic. Lloyd went jogging, often at night, in her home town of Ashland, Oregon. She photographed Ashland's response to the virus and wrote stories directly on the photographs about her experiences and ideas the photographs evoked in her. She saw the town's response, as a tightly-knit small community, to be a form of folk life.; 1 portfolio (18 photographs): color prints with original writing above and below with 2 prints on 1 card mount; 17 x 12 inch (Box 57)
    - Coronavirus, Ashland, Oregon, 2020, afc2018064_dc001; 20 still image files (jpg)
  - Subseries 2: Anti-nuclear movement
    - Ashland anti-nuclear, 1982-1983, AFC 2018/064: SL-21-01 – SL-21-07; 127 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); SL-21-01: Complete; SL-21-02: 30-35; SL-21-03: Complete 9-20, first strip lost; SL-21-04: Complete 2-20; SL-21-05: 2-27; SL-21-06: Complete, odd strip from roll; SL-21-07: Complete.; Kodak (Box 22)
    - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-21], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/1)
    - Ashland anti-nuclear activists, 1982-1983, AFC 2018/064: SL-23-01 – SL-23-19; 61 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); SL-23-01: John and Dot Fisher Smith; Frame 3; SL-23-02: Lloyd Family; Frame 6; SL-23-03: Marjory Kellogg: Frame 7; SL-23-04: Don Skinner; Frame 10; SL-23-05: David Kirkpatrick; Frame 6; SL-23-06: Patt Colwell; Frame 6; SL-23-07: John and Shannon Stahmer; Frame 12; SL-23-08: Philip Davidson, Oregon Shakespeare Festival; Frame 5; SL-23-09: Philip Arnold; Frame 5; SL-23-10: Wis Nelson; Frame 8 and Frame 12; SL-23-11: Father Robert Kruger; SL-23-12: Michael Leberer aka O'Rourke; Frame 6; SL-23-13: Penny Youngfeather; Frame 12; SL-23-14: Activist group; SL-23-15: "Peace" Kids for news advertisement; Frame 8; SL-23-16: Michael Touchette; Frame 6; SL-23-17: Mike and Annie Paup; SL-23-18: Andre Carpenter; Frame 11; SL-23-19: Marilyn Lenihan.; Kodak (Box 22)
    - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-23], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/3)
    - Portfolio 4: How One Town in Oregon is Saying No to the Bomb, 1982-1983, In 1982, citizen activists in Ashland, Oregon wanted to declare their town a nuclear free zone, following the example of the first nuclear free zones in Great Britain. The individuals spearheading the ballot measure for Ashland's ordinance ranged from housewives, nurses, and doctors to farmers, priests and students. First they conducted candlelight vigils, conducted meetings, and made eight hundred tapes about the nuclear peril to send to U.S. Congresswomen and Congressmen's wives. This was followed by a forty-three mile march north to protest at Litton Industries in Grants Pass, Oregon, manufacturer of guidance systems for cruise missiles. These efforts led to the passage of Ballot Measure 56. Other towns in the U.S. followed suit to pass nuclear free-zone ordinances in their towns and cities. Ashland town councilors then visited Great Britain to collaborate with anti-nuclear activists there. This portfolio, consisting of portraits and accompanying statements made by the activists, resulted in exhibitions, publications and presentations in the U.S. and Great Britain. It documents the key activists in Ashland's nuclear free-zone movement.; 1 portfolio (14 photographs): black-and-white gelatin silver prints; 8 x 10 inch (Box 46)
      - Print 1: John and Dot Fisher-Smith, (John) architect and planner; (Dot) initiator of Ashland Affinity Group for Creative Non-Violence. Participants in Livermore and Trident peace blockades. (John): "The kind of thinking that comes from engaging in nuclear power and nuclear weaponry results in setting 'acceptable' casualty levels such as the loss of twenty million Americans in a 'winnable' nuclear exchange, or the loss of, say, the state of Pennsylvania in an unfortunate power plant accident. People become ciphers in a giant computerized, intellectual chess game where the players have forgotten the meaning of the magic of life." (Dot): "What's required in these times is confrontation all along the way. I care enough about this issue to take risks. I'm putting my body behind my words. It's saying no to things you don't like. If I'm saying no to Trident submarine, it's quite clear I'm saying yes to life."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-01
      - Print 2: Susan and Tom Lloyd, Susan and Tom Lloyd, (Susan) photographer, (Tom) attorney for blockaders at Litton Industries. "My chronicle of Ashland's confrontation with the nuclear issue started as a photo-commentary...as it progressed, I realized my concerns went beyond what I viewed in my lens and had learned through hours of dialogue with the movement leaders. I realized this issue affected all mankind, and my most intense concern has been for the future of my child. Will he miss the opportunity of really experiencing childhood, growing up with fear of the bomb? What a weight for him to bear...if indeed, he has the chance to "grow up" at all. I must continue to do something, no matter how small: to live honestly, to question, to make a stand."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-02
      - Print 3: Don Skinner, Don Skinner, initiator of Measure 56, (Ashland's Nuclear Free Zone Ordinance). "Measure 56 provided an excellent opportunity for activity at the community level. I think the major benefit of passing the ordinance is that it doesn't depend on permission from Congress or action by President Reagan. It doesn't rely on some mega-corporation to provide us with a grant-in-aid, or ask the authorities and specialists to reach some nebulous agreement in the face of obviously compelling evidence. We just went ahead and did something, and now other communities are doing something too."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-04
      - Print 4: Dr. David Kirkpatrick, Dr. David Kirkpatrick, physician and psychiatrist, member of Southern Oregon chapter of Physicians for Social Responsibility. "We don't know what effect the threat of holocaust has on our children--we do know, psychologically and medically, that children do not have the defenses to deal with the nuclear issue that adults do. As such, they are more vulnerable. Newest research evidence from Boston psychiatrists shows that schoolchildren are growing up with a sense of hopelessness, despair, and depression about their future, believing they will have none. Who is to say whether this response of our children is less appropriate than the utter apathy of the greatest majority of American people who have a tunnel vision, comfort-zone existence? My greatest fear is of the middle-of the-roaders, the do-nothings...As Edmund Burke said: 'All that's required for evil to succeed is for good men to do nothing.'"; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-05
      - Print 5: Patt Colwell, Patt Colwell, member of CALS (Citizen Action for a Lasting Security), organizer for Measure 56. "Must we assume we have to have nuclear weapons? One of the members of the opposition said as a reason for not voting for Measure 56, 'My gosh, if every community in the country passed such an ordinance, then there would be no place left to store or manufacture nuclear weapons', and we said, 'That's precisely the point!"; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-06
      - Print 6: John and Shannon Stahmer, John and Shannon Stahmer, peace educators and war tax resistance organizers. (John) founder of Peace House, Ashland. (Shannon): "Once I was asked during a television interview on war tax resistance, 'Why is your approach so 'anti' everything?' Truly, it took me by surprise, because though I am resistant and unyielding in my stance to not participate in making nuclear weapons, my actions are motivated by a deep sense of love and connectedness to all living things." (John): "I was studying for the ministry when I got involved-I was studying spirituality and became aware of the spirituality of social justice. I began to see what was going on in the arms race as a moral issue. Now I feel very strongly that this is a life and death issue. Peace education has become my ministry."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-07